all right the other day I was just kind
of messing around thinking of different
things in my head and uh I started
thinking of ways that you could load the
the glutes mainly the glute medius and
so you know a little bit of the glute
Max dynamically while standing um
through through through a full range of
motion and I'm sure this has been
thought of before I just haven't seen it
before I'm sure that physical therapists
and maybe some past train coaches have
already thought of this movement but I
tried to search around and I couldn't
find anything so I'm just going to call
it the double the standing double hip
abduction so what I do is I stand on one
leg I'm going to bend this one I'm going
to come down into a little bit of hip
and and knee flexion kind of like a a
quarter squat but I'm also going to sink
into hip adduction and internal rotation
a little bit so this is what you don't
really want to do right normally but I'm
doing it for a reason I'm doing it so I
can move concentrically and
eccentrically through a full range of
motion so go down into a quarter squat
let this hip sink in so I'm getting a
stretch in these tissues right over here
and then from here I'm going to do
several different actions I'm going to
extend the knee extend the hip abduct
the hip and externally rotate and then
with this leg I'm going to do the same
I'm going to abduct this leg leg as well
so looks like this sink
down come up and raise this so I'm
trying to get maximum separation in my
hips here so sink
down come up sink
down come
up anyway I do about five of those and
my glutes are just screaming it really
works on the the glute medius muscle um
it's obviously easier on your dominant
leg the one that you're well for me my
left leg I'm better at balancing on that
most right-handed people will be better
at balancing on their left leg but the
other leg okay the secret isn't just to
squat down you're actually sinking
down and uh kind of this is not an easy
movement to do if if you're always you
know in neutral here but you've got to
actually sink down and try and stretch
this out as I come
up raise all the way up to here try and
get maximum
separation here here so what I like
about
this is I am working my glute medius
through a full range of motion on both
sides so both legs are getting a good
workout here not one or the other anyway
that's called
the uh standing double
hip
abduction and uh I think it's really
good and I'm also going to show you
another video where I do kind of a
similar concept from a quadraped
position but I really like these
movements give him a try